LINGAM SUNNY

SENIOR DEVELOPER

+91 9791060211

lingamsunny123@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

6+ years of experience in Electronic Data Interchange and Java development with good knowledge in application layers, presentation layers and databases. Aspire to be part of a value-based organization, where working comes as a challenge, skills could be harnessed to upgrade knowledge and simultaneously achieve organization's objectives in an efficient and self-motivated manner and obtain productive results in the work environment.

TECHNICAL SKILL

Tools: IBM Sterling Integrator, Gentran Integration Suite

Languages: Java

Frameworks: Spring, LightWell

EDI Standards: ASNI X12 and EDIFACT

Communication Protocols: HTTP, HTTPs, SFTP

Mapping File Formats: EDI, Positional (Flat files), iDoc (SAP).

ERP System: SAP

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

SRM University

Electronics and Instrumentation

WORK EXPERIENCE

TATA CONSULATNCY SERVICES - Systems Engineer CLIENT - Depository Trust & Clearing Corporation (DTCC)

12/2016 - 02/2019

Roles and Responsibilities

- Employed Agile methodology for Project Management & GIT for Version Control to manage the team.
- Directed the Application system design over Java/J2EE to prioritise security, robustness & transaction management.
- Designed and developed configuration in XML for Spring application.
- Created detailed documentation of the system.
- Participated in change and code reviews to understand the testing needs of the change components.

INFOSYS Limited - Senior Associate Consultant CLIENT- Alcon

Roles and Responsibilities

- Responsible for providing 24x7 Production and Operational support from offshore.
- Maintaining EDI knowledge repository and Coordinating EDI activities with trading partners.
- Responsible for fixing known bugs and to make changes as necessary, involved in code changes and testing. Dealt with translation errors in support activity and update the map in timely manner.
- Maintaining the communication activities (HTTP, HTTPS and SFTP) and handling the outages.
- Creating setup in lightwell framework for file flow with receive, split, translation and send rules.
- Tracking the files in lightwell framework if any failures.
- Interfacing lightwell framework partner information with SI by giving SAP parameters.
- Responsible for resolving and Mthe SLA for handling the Incidents & Work Orders.

NTT DATA SERVICE - Senior EDI Analyst

11/2020 - 01/2022

CLIENT - Halyard Global Products

Roles and Responsibilities

- Handling both Development and Support activities Using Gentran Server.
- Gentran server interfaced with Axway for AS2setup.
- Developing maps for EDI transaction sets like 810, 850, 855, 856 and Performed testing and validations using test data provided.
- Involved in maps conversion of EDI to Flat file, SAP IDOC and vice-versa.
- Involved in new Trading Partner setups based on the customer needs.
- Mapping and developing the interfaces as per the specifications.
- Testing the EDI files for all EDI errors.
- Responsible for providing 24x7 Production and Operational support from offshore and Weekly status reporting and On-Call support during weekends.

COGNIZANT - Senior Associate

01/2022 - 06/2022

CLIENT - Levi Strauss

Roles and Responsibilities

- Coordinated with business and trading partners for requirement gatherings for trading partner onboarding and enhancement requests
- Worked on creating mapping specs for partners as per requirement.
- Worked on Map changes as per spec in Sterling Integrator.
- Conducted end to end testing with trading partners and ERP system for the changes
- Warranty support after deployment.

COGNIZANT - Senior Associate

06/2022 - present

CLIENT - ALCON

Roles and Responsibilities

- Involved in new Trading Partner setups based on the customer needs.
- Coordinated with business and trading partners for requirement gatherings for trading partner onboarding and enhancement requests.
- Involved in maps conversion of EDI to Flatfile, SAP IDOC and vice-versa.
- Extensive mapping and configuration for the transactions like invoice and invoice list, orders and batched orders, ASN, order response.